<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Kieran Shah&#39;s Data Science Examples</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Kieran Shah&#39;s Data Science Examples</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 08 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Implemting Average Marginal Effects with Bayesian Ordinal Regression</title>
      <link>/2021/01/08/implemting-average-marginal-effects-with-bayesian-ordinal-regression/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2021/01/08/implemting-average-marginal-effects-with-bayesian-ordinal-regression/</guid>
      <description>The R package margins provides average marginal effects for any model developed with lm or glm, among many others. However, margins does not work with brms. Jack O’Bailey developed two functions for brms here. There are two functions in this text file. The first function gets the average marginal effects for continuous independent variables. The second function get the average marginal effects for categorical variables. The link compares the results of the two functions with the margins command from the package margins.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Covid Mapping with FSAs and Dissemination Areas</title>
      <link>/2020/08/28/covid-mapping-with-fsas-and-dissemination-areas/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/08/28/covid-mapping-with-fsas-and-dissemination-areas/</guid>
      <description>Covid Mapping Part 2The first post looked at how we can use the center of a Forward Sortation Area (FSA) into a Census Tract. However, as noted, this is a messy process. FSAs are large ares, see the Wikipedia page. Instead of this messy process, we can look at FSAs, and use Dissemination Areas from Census 2016 to fit those into FSAs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Covid Mapping</title>
      <link>/2020/08/26/covid-mapping/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/08/26/covid-mapping/</guid>
      <description>City of Toronto Covid Mapping ProjectThe purpose of this post it to use the Open Data Toronto portal to use their Covid-19 data, and to first map the data, and second, bring in Census 2016 data to show correlations between income, and other demographic variables and Covid-19 positive cases.
The full code can be found here.
Get the data:Anyone can download the data here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Prediction with Python</title>
      <link>/2020/08/06/prediction-with-python/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/08/06/prediction-with-python/</guid>
      <description>Using Python and Reticulate:Reticulate is a R package that allows us to implement python within an R markdown file. This post shows how to do some basic predictive analysis using the same NBA dataset we used in prior posts.
We first need to read in the data. Below is some basic code to bring in a csv file.
import pandas as pdimport numpy as npAnalyticalDS = pd.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Cases Analysis</title>
      <link>/2020/07/31/new-cases-analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/07/31/new-cases-analysis/</guid>
      <description>Analysis:The purpose of this analysis is to evaluate the impact of our three weather metrics on new Covid-19 cases in California. The complete and large dataset can be found here.
The complete code for this post can be found here:.
The basic California model will hypothesize that the stages of each opening should increase new cases after a week. Similarly, weather should work in a similar pattern. Better weather should encourage more outdoor activity, and we should see a drop in cases up until a certain point.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting Weather and Covid Data</title>
      <link>/2020/07/28/getting-weather-and-covid-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/07/28/getting-weather-and-covid-data/</guid>
      <description>Weather DataMany epidemiological experts have linked weather to rising or falling Covid-19 cases. The first two steps of the process of getting data is as follows:
The Covid-19 cases by county in the United States (US) can be found here:.
The weather data comes from Darksky. We use the package darksky. darksky is a wrapper for the API DarkSky provides.
The package darksky and its documentation is here:.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Get NBA Draft Data</title>
      <link>/2020/07/26/get-nba-draft-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/07/26/get-nba-draft-data/</guid>
      <description>Getting draft dataAn interesting aspect of evaluating average player length is looking at their original draft position. The below code uses Basketball Reference and rvest to pull the drafts from 1985 to 2010.
This post uses the two packages rvest and the tidyverse package.
The code below looks through the NBA draft pages on Basketball Reference. It pulls the html tag table.
When the code reads in the data, the first few variables do not have assigned variable names.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Survival Analysis</title>
      <link>/2020/07/26/survival-analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/07/26/survival-analysis/</guid>
      <description>The two previous posts have described the data available. This post will look to survival analysis to assess time until the end of a NBA career.
The code can be found here.
The first plot looks at the Kaplan Meier curves for both minutes played and seasons played by position.
As we can see, there is not a considerable difference between positions for the minutes played Kaplan-Meier curve.
Next, we look at the seasons played:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NBA Average Career Length</title>
      <link>/2020/06/30/nba-average-career-length/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/06/30/nba-average-career-length/</guid>
      <description>The purpose of this post is to show how to use the ballr package to get historical NBA data, and after getting the data, find the best metric to use to determine longevity.
BallrThe ballr package provides easy to use function to access the vast data resources on basketball-reference.com.
To get historical data for a defined group of players, we first pick a few given seasons. For our example, we pick the 2003 to the 2010 seasons.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Student Forecast Model</title>
      <link>/2020/06/07/student-forecast-model/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/06/07/student-forecast-model/</guid>
      <description>This post attempts to provide an example using simulated data of how to forecast student enrollment at a four-year college or university. It uses Markov chains with simulated data. The complete code to reproduce this post can be found here
Describe a model:In most North Americana four-year universities, students progress through the four-year curriculum, and then graduate after four years. However, some students leave after the first year, other after their third year.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 May 2016 21:48:51 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/</guid>
      <description>I am a statistician working on post-secondary issues at the University of Guelph. I work with different departments to create projections for future student counts. I also work on different program evaluations.
The purpose of this blog is to show some of the modelling work and data manipulation in Python and R that I have previously used in my current job, and previous employment. All of the examples are based on public data, and can be fully reproduced using the post itself, or the github code associated with the post.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>